Finding Aid for United Asian American Organizations (University of Michigan) Records 1990-1998
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
United Asian American Organizations (University of Michigan) Records 1990-1998, 1992-1997
United Asian American Organizations (University of Michigan)
1.5 linear foot
9849 Bimu 2
An umbrella organization of seven University of Michigan Asian and Pacific student organizations; documents aspects of Asian student communities at the university, includes administrative records, program files and publications
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The records were transferred from the United Asian American Organizations in February, 1998. Donor no. 8689
The record group is open for research.
The United Asian American Organizations (UAAO) was formed in the summer of 1990 with seven University of Michigan Asian Pacific organizations. UAAO was established to work in unity to overcome injustices facing Asian Pacific Americans, to promote awareness of Asian Pacific American cultures and traditions, and to establish a communication core for Asian Pacific American organizations and individuals at the University of Michigan.
UAAO is an umbrella group for Asian Pacific American (referred to as APA) organizations, clubs and students at the University of Michigan. UAAO is an independent organization, which is not dominated by any single community, organization, political party, or individual.
Currently UAAO is composed of a seven-member officer board, representatives from 18 student groups, and all interested APA students. Together these students comprise five committees working for the good of the APA Community: Programming, Finance, Advocacy, Internal Relations, and External Relations. UAAO provides a voice for its membership to speak out on issues such as education, university and government policy, discrimination as it pertains to Asian Pacific Americans. The organization also helps to administer scholarship programs and activities which support current and future Asian Pacific Americans.
The records of the United Asian American Organizations provide a good source of information on issues pertaining to the Asian Pacific American community and other minority groups at the University of Michigan. The United Asian American Organizations records are divided into four series: Administrative Records, Programs and Activities, Publications and Topical Files.
Subjects:
Asian Americans--Michigan.; Asian Americans--Social conditions.; Asian Americans--Societies.; Minority college students--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; United Asian American Organizations.; University of Michigan--Students--Societies, etc.
- Administrative Records
  The Administrative Records series mostly relates to the internal activities of the organization. The files include material about the organization's background, agendas and minutes, memos and budget material. The background and organization file highlights the goals, objectives, committee description, constitution and other general information about the structure of the organization. Agendas and minutes are arranged chronologically and they span the years from 1991 to 1997. There are no agendas and minutes for the first year of the organization. The correspondence file (1992-1997) shows interaction between the UAAO and other university units as well as with other Asian Pacific American member organizations. The memos cover the years 1992-1997. A researcher should note that no memos appear for the years 1990-1991.
  - Background and Organization (Box 1)
  - Agendas
    - 1991-1993 (Box 1)
    - 1994 (Box 1)
    - 1995-1996 (Box 1)
    - 1997 (Box 1)
  - Minutes
    - 1991-1992 (Box 1)
    - 1993 (Box 1)
    - 1994-1997 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence 1992-1997 (Box 1)
  - Memos 1992-1995 (Box 1)
  - United Asian American Organizations Annual Budget, July1994-June1995 (Box 1)
- Programs and Activities
  The Programs and Activities series documents United Asian American Organizations sponsored events and programs. These include UAAO community wide events, community services and internal events. The programs and activities series is divided into three subseries: Conferences, Projects and Lectures and Miscellaneous. Conferences are arranged chronologically. Projects and Lectures are arranged alphabetical by name of a project or lecture. Miscellaneous files include information on other UAAO programs and activities.
  - Conferences
    - Black Action Movement Conference Report 1990 (Box 1)
    - Asian Pacific American Youth Conference 1994 (Box 1)
    - Asian Pacific American Leadership Conference 1996 (Box 1)
    - Student Conference 1996 (Box 1)
  - Projects and Lectures
    - Black Volunteer Network 1995 (Box 1)
    - Colored Museum Project 1994 (Box 1)
    - Leadership 2017 1995, 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Dr. Martin Luther King Jr. Day 1994-1995, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Project Lighthouse 1993 (Box 1)
    - Twenty Fifth Annual Student Symposium "issues 94" (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Asian Pacific American Task Force Programs 1994-1995 (Box 1)
    - Asian Pacific American Events 1992-1997 (Box 1)
    - Publicity Material 1992-1997 (Box 1)
    - Planning and Tasks 1993-1997 (Box 1)
    - Minority Peer Advisors Training 1994 (Box 2)
- Publications
  The Publications series includes assorted journals, newsletters and booklets. The majority of the publications originate from different Asian Pacific American member organizations.
  - Assorted journals 1991-1996 (Box 2)
  - Assorted newsletters 1990-1997 (Box 2)
  - Booklets, 1994-1998 (Box 2)
- Topical Files
  The Topical Files series contains a variety of files about the organization's internal and external functions. The arrangement is alphabetical by topic. Some files provide a rich source for the researcher interested in the organization's involvement with different University of Michigan units.
  - Black Student Union 1992-1994 (Box 2)
  - Midwest Asian American Student Union Minutes/Agendas 1994 (Box 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1992-1994 (Box 2)
  - Office of Academic Multicultural Initiatives Communications 1993-1994 (Box 2)
  - Report of the Provost Task Force on Asian American Students 1991 (Box 2)
  - Social Events Policy 1992, 1994, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - United Asian American Organizations Election Material 1994-1996, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - United Asian American Organizations Email News 1992-1993 (Box 2)
  - United Asian American Organizations Spring/Summer Survey 1997 (Box 2)